Corinne Krych – +3395 095 13 85 – +336 28 34 61 18 – corinnekrych@gmail.com – 42 chemin des Bastides Villa 2, 06130 Grasse – Date of Birth: 12/02/1972 – French Citizen

Background Summary

Senior technical consultant with 15 years experience, 12 companies, worked in different environments and methodologies. Enthusiastic, curious and skilled.

Pragmatic thinker I will understand requirements and turn them into quality software and useful documentation.

http://corinnekrych.github.com

Open source projects & Conferences

GR8 Conf (Copenhagen) June 2012	Building a Groovy DSL (Speaker)
Mobile apps in minutes November 2012	Groovy Mag (Publication)
JS.Everywhere (Paris) November 2012	Hybrid mobile app in minutes not days (Speaker)
Grails eXchange (London) December 2012	User Interaction and Groovy DSL (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2012	HTML5 Games Hands-on (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2012	Building a Groovy DSL with user interaction (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2012	Hybrid mobile app in minutes, not days (Speaker)
3musket33rs	http://3musket33rs.github.com Grails Mobile plugins suite (Open source development)
RivieraGUG	http://www.rivieragug.org co-founder coolest GUG in France

Career history

Amadeus (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Software Engineer http://www.amadeus.com

March 2009 to Present

Join SellConnect team to develop Productivity Suite:

- design/implement DSL for scripting travel agent's cryptic reservation language using embedded groovy DSL
- implement translator migration (antlr)
- develop web2.0 UI using Aria Template (http://ariatemplates.com/), first Amadeus Open Source project Senior developer in Profile team:
- Coach junior team member, define use cases and tasks in a collaborative approach
- Implement OPS (Open Profile Suite) for American Express within aggressive deadlines, bringing new North American market opportunities for Amadeus,
- Initiate pragmatic technical documentation for developers (distributed team Nice and Waltham offices) on OPS business
- Present video conference functional walk-through meetings
- Interface with Profile back end and User Management (LSS) back end team
- Escalate and close follow up on issues, bring topics to architecture board.

Experian – Extelia (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Consultant http://www.extelia.fr

October 2008 to February 2009

Part of the « Plateforme Télécollecte » team, working on back office software for transferring and archiving of all *administrative* formalities (constitution, radiation etc...) between CFE (government company for formalities) and the court clerks:

- Designed and development of the java batch new platform « Formalités » using the Xml Régent Edi 2008 standard which support previous norms via XSL converter.
- Redesigned « build management system »: modules and dependencies, Maven, Artifactory, unit test strategy based on EasyMock.

Amadeus (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.amadeus.com

September 06 to February 08

Member of Software Engineering team (SDX):

- Enhanced development environment: Eclipse plugin packaging, build framework to install products,
- Initiated and maintained a wiki-based knowledge database on 'how to', FAQs and user/installation guides.
- Introduced dependencies management system to migrate monolithic applications into technical and business components using Ivy/Maven frameworks.

UBS (London UK), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.ubs.com

June 05 to May 06

Part of XTools team (development and infrastructure support for Equities IT developers across the world):

- Implemented maven and build system (ant) standards for the java teams.
- Structured Maven 1&2 repositories and maven-HUFS (UBS specific directory structure and deployment process) bridge.
- Introduced a Collaborative Software Development platform for UB IT Equities based on open source GForge product.
- Promoted and advised on best practices for building or refactoring J2EE applications.

Servista (London UK), Technical Team Leader

http://www.servista.com

November 04 to May 05

Servista develops solutions in customer care, billing, marketing and customer analytics. For the 'Operational Service Requests' Swing/Web Start application:

- Coached XP team of 5 developers (Agile methodology) to achieve weekly iteration and integration, automated build running unit test, keep it simple and test-driven approach.
- Liaised with marketing people (Client)
- Liaised with QA team and organize training session with future users.

BACS Limited (London UK), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.voca.co.uk

January 04 to November 04

BACS is the UK's automated clearing-house, which transfers funds between banks for the settlement of payments. As lead developer of the BACSTEL-IP Project:

- Coached the team using Agile methodology to meet tight deadlines.
- Introduced pair programming sessions
- Following a test-driven approach, re-instated unit tests (JUnit, In-container with Cactus and Mock Object)
- added coverage tool (Clover)
- automated incremental build (Cruise Control interfacing with Clear Case) to measure progress.
- Worked with SCM team to redesign ClearCase/ClearQuest to meet Agile approach

Marsh Inc. (Toronto Canada), Senior Software Designer

http://www.marsh.com

Oct 00 to Oct 02

Marsh Inc., world's leading risk and insurance services firm, is dealing with risk management, insurance-broking and program-management services. As a member of the e-business applications team, worked on Surety project, web based application to manage surety bond:

- Participated on development of MVC framework using Apache Struts Model for the work-flow, JSP and XML/XSL for the rendering.
- Developed EJB components (stateless session beans and BMP with TopLink) with IBM WebSphere Application Server. Migration of legacy CORBA Marsh Business Services.
- Liaised with business analyst team to produce RUP artefacts.

Department of the Solicitor General of Canada (Integrated Justice) (Toronto Canada),

Software Engineer

http://www.publicsafety.gc.ca

Dec 99 to Sept 00

Architectured a platform/language independent middle-ware layer for remote administrative tools through usage of CORBA.

Griechsen Gilchrist Ltd (London - UK), start-up Sep 99 to Oct 99

Prototyped a Java Web application to promote the JTS (Java Transaction Service) of Arjuna (Bluestone/ HewletPackward):

Trace Financial plc, (London UK), Developer http://www.tracegroup.com

Au 98 to Au 99

Developed new modules for Trafic in C++ for the Standard Settlement Instructions for ICON and OASYS.

Quaternove Paris (Paris France), Designer / Programmer http://www.quaternove.fr Jul 97 to Jul 98

Designed the object oriented model with the case tool **Objecteering (UML** methodology), Developed STD - billing application - for the Public French Electricity (EDF) in **C++**

Maestro: Filial of MATIF S.A Paris (Paris France), Developer http://www.matif.fr Jan 97 to Jun 97

Maestro IT division of (French future exchange and derivatives market)

Designed and developed with **Visual C++**, Tenor, a front and middle office software for banking application.

Avenir Havas Média, Paris (Paris France)
Developer
http://www.havas.fr

Feb 96 to Dec 96

Designed STRADA (geomarketing application) database, using **MERISE** methodology, GUI implementation with **Delphi**.

Education and Training

April 2004	Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition 1.3 (CX-310-080)
March 2003	IBM XML and Related Technologies Certification (test 141)
October 1999	Java2 SUN Certification (310-025)
June 1999	Certificate in Advanced English (CAE) of Cambridge
January 1999	"Informix-OnLine Dynamic Server 6/7 Database Administration"
March 1998	Sybase trainings: "Administration of SQL Server 11", "Transact-SQL System 11.0"
1991 – 1996	E.S.I.E.A. (Paris V) Master's degree in computer services.
1990	Baccalauréat C (French scientific A-level).